Hello, welcome to Market Sense
Tamil. Today in this video, we will be discussing a complete review of a product called
I Protect Smart Super from Ionic. We will discuss in detail the
positive and negative aspects of it.
We will also
discuss who will be able to use it.  If this is your first
time visiting my channel, I will be posting useful content related to
stock market
plans and insurance for you on this channel
.  Subscribe to my channel and
click the bell icon.  So that
you will receive a notification when I upload a video.  And if
any of you need consulting on health insurance,
life insurance, stock market
investments,
or want to purchase life insurance or health
insurance, feel
free to contact us and
avail our services.  We will
come and provide 100% after-purchase service from here
.   Those who purchase from
us already
know that.  Let's
go into the video now.  Let's first come and
talk about ICICI Bank.  This company has been in the
life insurance market in India for more than
24 years
and the fact that one of the largest
private banks in India, ICICI Bank, is backing this
particular ICICI as a life insurance
company is
a huge positive for this particular company
.
If you look at the claim settlement ratio of this particular company, it is 98%.  So, you can't just
say that this is the best in the industry
.  Butt butt is a decent claim
ratio for this particular bond.   So, I
don't know what the claim settlement ratio is. So, if 100 claims
come in, 98 of them
are settled. That's what
this 98% claim settlement ratio
means.  And
in terms of the amount settlement ratio, you will get
92.5%
.  So,
why do we look at this amount settlement ratio? If so, the
claim settlement ratio of some companies is
very good and extra
.  But their amount
settlement ratio will
be comparatively low.  The reason for that is
that
in terms of the number of policies, they have settled a lot of claims,
but when
policies with a large value of 5 crores, 10 crores, 15 crores, come in and they don't settle them,
their claim
settlement ratio
is extraordinary.  But when you compare their out-of-pocket
settlement ratio, it's a
shame.  So that's why we
see that outstanding settlement ratio.  This is
not the best in the industry, but when it comes to comparability, they only give a
discount and an amount
settlement ratio. Also,
in terms of complaint volume,
14 complaints
are registered out of 10,000 customers.  If you look at this too, it's
not the best in the industry.  But
we should look at an average compliant volume
.  We know from this that even with
this particular complaint
volume from ICICI products, they are still
improving their service
.  This particular product, the
Hi-Product Smart Plus, comes in
three variants
.  They offer three variants: Life, Life Plus, and Life
Rebalancing
.  Let's take a look at
each variant one by one.   Let's
come first and see the live variant.
Now, for the life variant,
you will also get a death benefit
.  Or some individual
comes and they come and they come and they sued for an Any Number of Eights
cover. Maybe they
sued for you for an example.
Then they sued for cover until their 70th birthday.
And at that
age of 70, something happened to that individual.
Then that person comes to your family and comes to
that name
.  So this is how the normal death
benefit works.  So this
comes in this particular policy and comes in the base
cover and comes to you.  This is
how all term plans work
.  But here
they come and give you an extra cover, saying that it is a terminal illness cover, without you having to pay any extra premium.  So that's a
very positive thing,
especially for this particular policy.
I'll
tell you how it works.  What if there is a terminal illness? An individual patient will
not survive for more than six months. Two
doctors, independent medical
practitioners, come and get
recognized by the Indian Medical Association
and also
from the company side.
They come and get an individual patient who will not survive for six months. If they do the certification,
that is what we
call terminal illness. So if
they
do the certification, you will immediately
see the entire cover. For example, if you have
taken a 1 crore cover, then only
that 1 crore will come and come immediately and
give it to the individual client.  That customer will give it to you
.  So, there are opportunities for
them to use that amount for their personal medical
expenses as well
.  So this is a
very, very
positive thing about this particular policy.  Because you don't have to
pay any extra premium and it comes with a
rider,
which is a positive thing.   If
you choose the second option, Life
Plus will come with this Life Plus and you will get a
death benefit.
Thermal illness will come with it.   The
thermal illness rider will also arrive.  You can
also pay an extra premium and
avail the accidental death benefit.  So, let me give you an example of how this accidental death
benefit works
.  An
individual came and took a cover of 1 crore
.
They have taken out a 50 lakh accidental cover.  If that
individual dies,
they will receive 1 karo, regardless of any type of death
.  It
could be a natural death or an accidental death, and
they
would get 1 crore.  But if they died in an accident,
then they
would get that extra 50 lakhs.  Because the base
cover is 1 crore and
he has taken an extra 50 lakhs for accidental damage, so
that extra 50 lakhs will be added to
the cover and they will
get it.  Only if he dies accidentally.   So they
come and say that's what accidental cover is
.  So, it's one thing to note that the premium for this will be comparatively
cheaper than the premium you pay for the base death benefit cover for a normal base plan
.  And
this particular policy can provide
you with a maximum of up to 3 crores
.  And
there is an age limit.  You can only get this policy until you turn 85 and then come and get
this particular policy and
come to the Accidental Death Benefit.
It came and this particular policy was a
check.  And if you
look at the third variant, I will give you a chart of how
life rebalancing works.
So, if you
look at this, for the first
10 years after you take the policy, there is
no death benefit. In the first 10 years, the death
benefit starts at 25% and increases every year
.  Once you complete the 10th year,
you
will receive 100% of the Sum Issue from the 11th year onwards. The more Sum Issue you
make, the more it will start to cover you
.  Similarly, if
you opt for the accidental
death benefit,
you will get 75% of the benefit in the first year.
After that, it gradually decreases and
reaches zero in the 11th year.  Now what if
you come and get your
starting age and your
accidental death cover increases.   The
accidental death benefit cover
is increased.  The base cover will become gummy.
Eventually, after the 11th year,
your full and full base death
benefit will become 100%.  And the
accidental death cover comes and the cummi
becomes zero.
I definitely won't see this as a recommendation if I come across this particular policy.
Definitely, come and get the
base cover anyway. When you buy a
base, that is, a death benefit on a sum assured,
you will be covered in the event of any kind of death
.  On top of that, you
pay an extra premium and then you come and
take out your own accidental death benefit cover.  So, when you came and
took the base cover, you had an
accidental crush.   Even if you
die in an accident, you will
get cover. In that case, you
will have to pay extra and take it out, which is
not necessary. If you
look at the variations of that cover, the
base sum comes out very
low, and you only get 25% in the first year,
so that is also a
high-risk matter.  That's why it's not
recommended.  Now, if you
come and want it,
you can come and take it on the life of that life insurance policy.
That's
my advice, my opinion.
You can add a critical illness rider to this policy
.
The product that was there before, called Hypertech Smart, has arrived, and you can
come and add 34 critical illnesses
.  It came and accelerated
critical illness.  So if you take a cover of 1 crore,
you can
opt for a critical illness cover of 20 lakhs, but
you can opt for it within that 1 crore.  So if
that client comes and is critically
affected and loses 20 lakhs,
this overdraft
will cover the loss of 80 lakhs.  So it
came and the old policy was like that.
So if you look at this updated criticality,
they give you two lists of diseases.
One comes with 20 criticality, the other
comes with 60 criticality, so there will
be a premium like 20, and there will be a
premium like 60.
They cover the maximum for 20 years
.
As for the entry age, you can come up to the age of 55 and apply for
this particular
criticality
.
You cannot enter beyond the age of 55.  You can come and get the cover until you reach the maximum
age of 75, and that
criticality will be removed
.  I'll
tell you the example, you've taken your cover of 1 crore
.  If you use criticality for 50 lakhs,
then if
you are affected by a criticality or any criticality, then
that 50 lakhs will come and come immediately and give it to
that particular client.
After that, the
premium for that criticality for that 50 lakhs will
come and become a profit. There is no need to pay more than that.
You
will just continue to do the summer show on death. So this is how this
criticality comes and works.  Now, if you
come here and look at both the list for 20 criticality
and then the list for 60 criticality,
I'll give you a screen shot.
So, pass it and
take the screenshot you need.  So here
comes the list of criticality.  So,
all of this is covered by this particular policy
.  The iProduct Smart
Plus option has arrived, and among the additional benefits
this plus offers you is the
premium break.
You are in a financial crisis.  You
can't just come and pay the premium for a year.   You
can make this particular policy yourself.  You
may not pay premium for 12 months.  But when you
do this, you have to have a cap between one premium
break and another premium
break for 5 years,
and also
you
can't take this premium break for the last three years.   If something untoward happens during the
year you took that premium break, the
policy will come into effect and
cover you.
That shirt will go to the nominee.  But they will detect the
premium for that particular year and come to the balance and they will come and settle
it and also come and come and
come in one year and
even if you have opted for riders, you do not
need to pay any GST for that. But next year, if you
pay that premium within the grace period and pay the premium that
you did not pay last year and the
premium for next year, then the
policy will come and remain active and continue as it is. So when it
comes,
you should come
seriously and come and follow it.
And
as for discounts, they
won't give you any single pack even after the first-year discounts come.  But the
limited plan gets 15% off, the regular plan gets
20% off, and
also for women, they get
15% off on women's policies.
Not just for the first year, they
give you discounts on the overall premium.  That means
you can buy the policy without having to come to the store with the above policy
.  And also, you come and
So I
came to the product spot and told you about
marriage and child birth.
So it's the same here too.
They will come to the wedding, get 50%, and then come and
give an additional summer show.
Similarly, for the birth of your first child,
you can take an extra 25% on top of that
.  You can come to the second child and
take 25%.  Okay, if you're taking a 1 crore cover,
then
you can take an extra 50 lakhs for getting married
.
Another 25 lakhs for the first child and then another
25 lakhs when the next child arrives, that means an overall 2
crores cover.  And
what is another additional future that you are getting? If
you have come and bought a home loan,
it is a displacement.
If that is the case,
you can come and buy a 100% life
cover extra with you.  So this is the
life stage protection that they offer,
but this is all just paste-
on underwriting.  This will only happen if So comes and
underwrites and gives permission for this
.
And also, what other extra
feature are they offering?
They're giving an option like Insta Payment.  So this is only for those who come
here and have a policy of more than 1 crore
.  So, in this
option, if an individual impersonation
occurs, their nominee comes and claims and
provides the necessary documents, they will
release 3 lakhs within 24 hours, that is, immediately
.  So that when it comes,
they can use that 3 lakh for emergencies, for a funeral or something like that
.  That future comes with this
particular policy and
they give you extras.  And
also, you can come and change the premium payment term for
this particular policy
.  Generally, when you
come to a policy and decide on the premium payment
term, there
are many options.
There are many options like regular limited pay, 5 pay, 10 pay, 15 pay, etc. in the age office.  So, if you came here and chose one option,
then
you can continue with that for the entire policy period if you come back.  But
they give you an option to change it when you get to this particular policy
.  Now that the initials have arrived,
you should have gone to regular pay.  That's a
condition, you have
to go to regular pay.  What is a regular policy? If
you come and take a policy and
take it until the age of 75, then it is a
regular policy. If
you take that policy and also come and take this particular
policy and
pay the premium for three years, then
after that,
you come and take the policy and get the
limited pack and you can come and
make a shift.  So for this
limited package, the
limited package that you have applied for should be available
and the underwriting team should also come and
accept it.  Similarly, if
you make a change, for
example, it has come and gone during one policy period,
then if you make the change,
the
change will come and take effect on the next policy anniversary
.  After that, whatever you decide to do with Limited, it will be like paying
extra premiums and
continuing with the policy
.  Features like the smart excess benefit
are very attractive in this particular policy.  So, you
can come and get back the entire premium you paid.  That's the option I used for
this smart exit.  So
let's see how this works.  Now, when you talk about premium, the
premium you paid for the rider will not be subject to GST
.  Nodal premiums are
extra because the
premium you paid for loading will not be returned.  Only the
basic death benefit will return the
entire premium you paid
.  So for that,
you should have renewed this policy for 25 years
.
You should only come and exercise if you are over 60 years old.
And also, you have the option to change the premium paying
term for this particular policy
.  So, if
you have changed the premium paying term,
then only after three years of making the change,
you will be able to exercise this particular policy and this exit benefit
.  So this is where
this smart excess benefit comes in. Those
who need a good future come in at the last
minute and this policy comes in and you can
surrender it.  And also,
what is another check point here? If
the last 5 years have come, this
particular policy has come, and you cannot exercise this spot
exit benefit,
then a
check point has come, and
in terms of these payouts, they are giving lump sum options. So this is normal in
all companies, so you use the cover for
1 crore, then the lump sum will come and settle the death
benefit. Then
another
income option will
come, so who will be able to claim the income? If so,
then a lump sum
cannot be handled.
They should be that kind of individual.  When
you come to them and make an income option,
they will come and
give you that sum of money for 10 years.   When you
divide it like that, every
month you will get 0.83%
of the overall sum, and you will keep getting
monthly income
.  So it will
be like that.  And also, if you die in the
first year, you
can immediately receive only that income for the next immediate year.   If
you buy it like that, they will
come and give you a free gift in the first year.  For the
next nine years, you will receive
0.80%
of the sum as a usher and continue to provide you with income
.  Now that
option is here.  And
thirdly, if you look at it, they
give you the Lamsum and Income option.  So, if you come here and buy a
shirt for 50%, you
can make a profit. For example, if you
come here and buy a policy for 2 crores,
then 50% is 1 crore.  Now, if
you come and invest that 1 crore, and
invest it as income, and the
income that is in balance comes, and the cover comes and spreads it for 10, 10
years, and every month
comes and says 0.83% of the total,
you will have earned
income.  And the
fourth option comes and they tell you it's an increasing income
option
.  So this increasing income
option will come to you and will keep increasing
your income year after year
.  For
example, if you come and take a cover of 1 crore, the first year they
come and give
you 1 crore
10 lakh and divide it and give you a monthly income
.  So come next year, they'll
give you 10% off that summer and increase it.  This kind of thing keeps
coming and going every year
.  If you come over and look at the
amount you will receive in 10 years, it will
be 145% of the sum.  That means if you take 1 crore power, it will be
like you get 1.45 lakh and receive a death benefit.  So
obviously, if this payout
option comes along and you want the lump sum income, lump sum income, or increase
income option, you should
opt out first because there
are chances that it will become a dependency and the premium will change.  Let's look at
the illustration here.  Now,
in terms of illustration, people who are over
35 years old are the most important.  We
came to them and gave them a quote for coverage until they were 70 years old
.
Life cover comes in 1 car and accidental
death cover comes in 50 lakhs.  Critical
illness cover came in at 30 lakhs.  So if you
come to that and talk about the first year cover and
see the premium for premium life cover, you will get
15,759.
So, from here on out, you will get the Death
Benefit and Terminal Rider
.
Combine both, because when the terminals arrive,
you will get Freya.  So, the
first year premium is 15759, and
from the second year, it is 18000.
This is what you get for accident, so we
took 50 lux, right? So, for
critical cases, we
took 30 lux.  So
the premium for that comes to 16547,
so the total comes to you, in the first year it
comes to 35306, in the second year it
comes to 3557, you pay it. So is there this
surrender benefit or not?
After 25 years, you can come and get
the policy and you can exit it.
That's it.  Now, when it comes and you
exit, you will
only get back the premium you paid for this death benefit
.  There
is no actual death benefit and the premium you pay for critical illness will
not be returned to you.  If you get a critical
illness,
you will only be covered for 20 years.   If you
look here, you
know.  You get natural cover and
cover up to 78 inches.
That cover has been around for 20 years since Butt came along and Criticalness came along
.  So, come on, come on, you'll have your
cover expired by September 2045
.  So, when it comes, you have to come and
put it in your mind.  And
look at another quotation.  I
have taken policy cover up to the same Saudi age, so if you
look at them, you
can see if they are clear to you.
We have taken 1 karor.  50 lakh rupees came and
actional death.  Criticality will come and 15
lagbee will come and you will have to run until
September 2045
.  Because after 20 years, they will
come to the maximum and give you cover.
So they
won't come over and cover it.  You will have coverage
until September 15, 2015, once both are in place
.  So, if you
come in the first year, you will get a discount of 27,409 and a
12.5% ​​discount on your salary
.  From the second year, you will have to pay
31,321 for life insurance
.  When you look at the total overall, if you come with a natural death cover of
3000 and a critical cover of 24771, it will
be like this: in the first year, you pay 55177, and in the second year, you pay 59000.
And when you surrender,
you get
whatever you paid for the base death benefit, and when
you surrender this policy after 25 years, that means
you get the special exit value when you die
.  We have discussed in great detail the positives and negatives of the Eye Protect Spot Plus
product
.   I
hope you will really enjoy this video.  If
you found this video useful
, please like it
.  Tell us your thoughts in the comments
.  If any of your friends and
family members are researching to purchase term insurance,
share this video with them.  So that would
be beneficial for them.